Guide to the Mister Rogers' Neighborhood Collection, 1955-2003 SC.1976.05
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Non-MRN Programs, 1975-1994; XII.
  - Other Non-MRN Programs, 1977-1994; 3.
    This subseries contains materials from three other projects or television programs that Fred Rogers was a part of. The Let's Talk About It pamphlets were written by Rogers and designed to give advice to parents on certain common aspects of childhood, like going to school, going to the dentist, and experiencing the death of a loved one. The pamphlets went hand-in-hand with the Let's Talk About It TV specials that Rogers also produced. Fred Rogers' Heroes was a television special highlighting four people who were helping children across America and enacting change in their neighborhoods. The press kit for the special includes photographs and press releases. Real Pittsburghers was also a television special which profiled 12 people from Pittsburgh, including Fred Rogers. This special was not created by Fred Rogers or Family Communications. The program description lists the 12 people who were profiled, and lists Rick Sebak as one of the producers.
    - Let's Talk About It pamphlets, 1977-1982 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Fred Rogers' Heroes press kit, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Real Pittsburghers program description (Box 18, Folder 17)
- Newspaper Articles and Clippings, 1963-2000; XIII.
  This series contains newspaper clippings (collected by media monitoring services) about Rogers and Mister Rogers' Neighborhood, organized alphabetically according to topic. It is unclear who collected the articles, whether the Rogers or Family Communications. Presumably there was material containing topics T-Z which the archives does not possess.
  - Acquistion of MRN collection, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Activities for children, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Advice given by Fred Rogers, 1977-1988 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Alike and Different, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Anniversaries, 1973-1992 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Appearances and visits, 1969-1993 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Awards, citations, and honors, 1969-1986 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Awards, citations, and honors, 1987-2000 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Berkeley Publishing Corporation, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Betamax, 1986-1987 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Books, 1974-1989 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Bowling Green visit, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Brockett's Productions, 1987-1988 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Burger King controversy, 1984-1987 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Cable and public television view on MRN, 1979-1986 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Captions photographs, 1974-1987 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Celebrations Week, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Children and TV, 1973-1989 (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
  - Children's concert Seattle visit, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Children's Festival, 1986-1987 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Children's Museum, 1985-1987 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Children's shows other than MRN, 1987-1989 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Closed caption viewing of MRN, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Columns written by Rogers, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Commencement speeches by Rogers, 1985-1988 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Comparisons to Daryl Rogers, 1985-1988 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Comparisons to David Byrne, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Comparison to George Bush, 1988-1989 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Computers or software, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Contribution to Heinz campaign, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Corporation for Public Broadcasting, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Criticism and reviews, 1969-1986 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Criticism and reviews, 1987-1989 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Crusade for Mr. Rogers, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Dance Week, 1986-1987 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Day care, 1983-1988 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Death, divorce, and other catastrophes, 1986-1990 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Eat n Park menu, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Entertainers Johnny Carson, David Copperfield, etc., 1985-1988 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Events and Meetings with Mister Rogers, 1986-1986 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Families Week, 1980-1985 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Feature articles and interviews magazines, 1969-1985 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Feature articles and interviews from magazines, 1988-1998 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Feature articles and interviews from magazines, newspapers, newsletters, and program guides, 1967-1984 (Box 21, Folder 10-11)
  - Feature articles and interviews from magazines, newspapers, newsletters, and program guides, 1985-1986 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Feature articles and interviews from magazines, newspapers, newsletters, and program guides, 1987-2000 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Food articles, 1986-1988 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Food Week, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Fred's thoughts on MRN, 1986-1989 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Funding for PBS, 1974-1988 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Grants, 1967-1987 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Guest, cast, producers, appearances, 1970-1987 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Guest, cast, producers, appearances, 1970-1987 (Box 23, Folder 1-3)
  - Handwriting analysis of Mister Rogers, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Holidays, 1986-1988 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Hospitals, 1974-1988 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Idlewild Park, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Insight Into Childhood, 1984-1986 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Josephine the Short-Neck Giraffe, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Make A Wish, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Making and Creating Week, 1985-1986 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Making Mistakes (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Margaret McFarland, 1987-1988 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Michael Jackson, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Migrants, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1974-1986 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1987-1989 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Mister Rogers' appointment as Pitt adjunct faculty, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Mister Rogers and Josie Carey, 1988-1991 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - MRN operas, 1973,1984 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Mister Rogers' philosophy, 1974-1987 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Music as education, 1985-1987 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Music of MRN, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Music related, 1974-1987 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Nantucket visit, 1984-1989 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Neighborhood of Make Believe, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - No and Yes Week (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Nuclear plant worker fired, 1984-1985 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Parodies and caricatures, 1985-1989 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Paul Lally interview, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - PBS scheduling, 1967-1973 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - PBS scheduling, 1974-1977 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - PBS scheduling, 1984-1986 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - PBS scheduling, 1987-1988 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Penguin Show, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Pets and talking to families about pets, 1987-1989 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Playing, toys, and dolls, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Playthings Week, 1986-1987 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Products, games, and toys, 1986-1987 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Psychology of child development, 1983-1989 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Public Broadcasting and the black audience, 1973-1974 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Public opinon of Mr. Rogers and MRN, 1969,1991 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Puppets, 1974-1985 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Quality of children's programs, 1982-1986 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Quality of children's programs, 1985-1987 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Reality of Mister Rogers controversy, 1984-1987 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - References to books, films, and pamphlets, 1974-1989 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Religious affiliations, 1963-1989 (Box 26, Folder 10)
- Oversize Materials, 1973-2001; 1973-1976; XIV.
  This series contains oversize materials, most of which consists of the Family Communications newsletter, Around the Neighborhood. The newsletter was geared towards parents, but also included content and activities for children.
  - Around the Neighborhood, 1973-1974 (Box 27a, Folder 1)
  - Around the Neighborhood, 1974-1975 (Box 27a, Folder 2)
  - Around the Neighborhood children's activities and mailings (Box 27a, Folder 3)
  - City Paper with paint by numbers Rogers on the cover, 2001 (Box 27a, Folder 4)